《曼达洛人》前情提要
原创翻译  双语字幕
小小的猎物
Such a large bounty
最新连载海外影视剧下载
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
能有如此巨额的赏金
for such a small package.
我的盔甲不太结实了
My armor has lost its integrity.
我可能又要重新做了
I may need to begin again.
翻译     哈里星球    RiverSide152
我必须警告你  它会非常惹眼的
I must warn you. It will draw many eyes.
翻译     星星与野狗    累
他们都恨你  曼达人
They all hate you, Mando.
如何才能向我最重要的合作伙伴表达感激呢
Now, how can I show my gratitude to my most valuable partner?
校对     星星与野狗    累
他们会怎么做
What are they doing with it?
我没问  这违反工会规定
I didn't ask. It's against the Guild Code.
时间轴     Caroline
后期     累
总监     星星与野狗
让开  我要去我的飞船
Step aside. I'm going to my ship.
你把猎物放下  我可能会让你过去
You put the bounty down and perhaps I'll let you pass.
他们之中有多少人有追踪器
How many of them had tracking fobs?
他们都有  他们都有
All of them. All of them!
星球大战
我会抓住你的
I'm gonna get you.
快跑  他们又来了
Go, go, go! They're back!
-快跑  -快躲起来
- Go! - Run for cover.
-快进去  -妈妈
- Get inside! - Mama!
妈妈
Mama!
-妈妈  -快跑
- Mama! - Go!
-妈妈  -雯塔
- Mama! - Winta!
妈妈
Mama!
来
Come on.
曼达洛人
第一季  第四集
避难所
别乱碰
Stop touching things.
索尔根  星系中森林覆盖的行星
我们看看  索尔根
Let's see. Sorgan.
好像没有星际港  没有工业中心
Looks like there's no star port, no industrial centers,
人烟稀少
no population density.
贫瘠之地
Real backwater skug hole.
再理想不过了
Which means it's perfect for us.
准备好保持低调放松一两个月了吗
You ready to lay low and stretch your legs for a couple of months,
你这个小旺普鼠
you little womp rat?
谁也找不到我们
Nobody's gonna find us here.
听好了  我要出去看看
Listen. I'm gonna go out there and I'm gonna look around.
应该不会太久
It shouldn't take too long.
不许乱碰
Now, don't touch anything.
我去找个住处  然后回来接你
I'll find us some lodging, then I'll come back for you.
你乖乖待在这
You stay right here.
待在这  不要动
You stay. Don't move.
明白吗
You understand?
很好
Great.
算了  走吧
Oh, what the hell? Come on.
欢迎  旅行者  有什么需要的吗
Welcome, travelers. Can I interest you in anything?
给小家伙来点骨头汤
Bone broth, for the little one.
你运气不错
Oh, well, you're in luck.
我刚刚宰了个格林杰兽  汤有很多
I just took down a grinjer, so there's plenty.
要不要给你也盛上一碗
Can I interest you in a porringer of broth as well?
-一碗就行  -好的
- Just the one. - Very well.
那边的那个  她是什么时候来的
That one over there. When did she arrive?
上周我就看见她在这了
I've seen her here for the last week or so.
-她来这有什么公干  -公干
- What's her business here? - Business?
索尔根没什么公干  所以我也不知道
Oh, well, there's not much business in Sorgan, so I can't say.
她看着不像伐木工  谢谢先生
She doesn't strike me as a log runner. Well, thank you, sir.
我马上就把汤端来
I will get that broth to you as soon as possible,
再送你一壶斯波奇茶
and I will throw in a flagon of spotchka just for good measure.
我这就拿来
I will be right back with that.
帮我看着点孩子
Keep an eye on the kid.
遵命  先生
Yes, sir.
想喝点汤吗
You want some soup?
恩多之战以后  我基本上都在肃清余孽
Saw most of my action mopping up after Endor.
主要是前帝国的军阀们
Mostly Ex-Imperial Warlords.
他们希望可以低调迅速
They wanted it fast and quiet.
他们用运输舰派遣我们
They'd send us in on the drop ships.
没有支援  只靠我们自己
No support, just us.
后来帝国消亡的时候  开始了政治斗争
Then when the Imps were gone, the politics started.
我们成为维和部队  保护代表  镇压暴动
We were peacekeepers, protecting delegates, suppressing riots.
这可不是我的初衷
Not what I signed up for.
你怎么到这里了
How'd you end up here?
姑且算是提前退休吧
Let's just call it an early retirement.
我知道你是工会的
Look, I knew you were Guild.
我以为你要追捕我  所以我下手才那么狠
I figured you had a fob on me. That's why I came at you so hard.
我猜到了
Yeah, that's what I figured.
谢谢你的款待
Well, this has been a real treat,
除非你还想再来一轮
but unless you wanna go another round,
有人先走一步了  而我是先来的
one of us is gonna have to move on, and I was here first.
看来这个星球已经有人占了
Well, looks like this planet's taken.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
打扰一下  先生
Excuse me, sir.
有什么事吗
There something I can help you with?
掠夺者
Raiders.
我们有钱
We have money.
所以你们觉得我是雇佣兵吗
So, you think I'm some kinda mercenary?
你是个曼达洛人  是吧
You are a Mandalorian, right?
或者至少穿着曼达洛盔甲
Or at least wearing Mandalorian armor.
这确实是曼达洛盔甲  对吧
That is Mandalorian armor, right?
-确实是  -看吧  我告诉他了
- It is. - See? I told him.
我读过很多关于你们的人...的族人的资料
Sir, I've read a lot about your people... Tribe.
-如果里面有一半是真的  -我们有钱
- If half of what I read is true... - We have money.
-多少钱  -我们的全部家当  先生
- How much? - Everything we have, sir.
-所有的收成都被偷了  -磷虾  我们捕磷虾
- Our whole harvest was stolen. - Krill. We're krill farmers.
我们煮斯波奇茶  全村凑钱了
We brew spotchka. Our whole village chipped in.
不够
It's not enough.
你确定吗  你都不知道任务是什么
Are you sure? You don't even know what the job is.
但我知道这不够  祝你好运
I know it's not enough. Good luck.
这是我们全部的钱了
This is everything we have.
下次收获之后可以再给你钱
We'll give you more after the next harvest.
走吧  我们回去
Come on. Let's head back.
我们花了一整天才到这里
Took us the whole day to get here.
现在却要毫无保护地
Now we have to ride back with no protection
飞回那个偏远的地方
to the middle of nowhere.
你们住哪里
Where do you live?
农场  你没听我说吗
On a farm. Weren't you listening?
我们是农民
We're farmers.
偏远地方的农民吗
In the middle of nowhere?
没错
Yes.
你们有农舍吗
You have lodging?
当然有
Yeah. Absolutely.
很好  上来帮忙
Good. Come up and help.
我还需要一样东西
I'm gonna need one more thing.
给我那些钱
Give me those credits.
准备好再战一场了吗
Ready for round two?
所以我们基本就是为了一顿饭钱
So, we're basically running off
帮人打炮一群掠夺者吗
a band of Raiders for lunch money?
他们让我们在偏远的地方落脚
They're quartering us in the middle of nowhere.
据我所知  对于你这种处境的人
Last I checked, that's a pretty square deal
这笔交易已经很合理了
for somebody in your position.
最坏的情况就是开枪
Worst case scenario, you tune up your blaster.
最好的情况就是我们威慑住他们
Best case, we're a deterrent.
我觉得这些树林里不会有
I can't imagine there's anything living in these trees
前震击士兵搞不定的生物
that an ex-shock trooper couldn't handle.
各位  他们来了
Everyone, they're here!
快来
Come on.
看起来他们很高兴见到我们
Well, looks like they're happy to see us.
看起来是
Looks like.
-你好  -他好可爱
- Hi. - He's so cute.
请进
Please come in.
希望这里够舒服
I hope this is comfortable for you.
不好意思  我们只有谷仓
Sorry that all we have is the barn.
这就可以
This will do fine.
我在这里放了些毯子
I stacked some blankets over here.
谢谢  你真好心
Thank you. That's very kind.
这是我女儿  雯塔
This is my daughter, Winta.
我们这里很少有人来
We don't get a lot of visitors around here.
她不习惯见到陌生人
She's not used to strangers.
这名好心人会保护我们不受坏人侵扰
This nice man is going to help protect us from the bad ones.
谢谢你
Thank you.
走吧  雯塔  别打扰我们的客人了
Come on, Winta. Let's give our guests some room.
-在吗  -请进
- Knock, knock. - Come in.
我可以喂他吗
Can I feed him?
没问题
Sure.
你饿吗
Are you hungry?
我能跟他玩吗
Can I play with him?
没问题
Sure.
来吧
Come on.
-我不觉得...  -他们没事的
- I don't think... - They'll be fine.
-我不...  -他们没事的
- I don't... - They'll be fine.
我拿了些食物过来
I brought you some food.
我看你在那里没有吃东西
I noticed you didn't eat out there.
我放在这里就走了
I'll leave it here for when I go.
你真细心
That's very thoughtful of you.
介意我问个问题吗
Do you mind if ask you something?
说吧
Go ahead.
你有多久没卸下盔甲了
How long has it been since you've taken that off?
自从昨天
Yesterday.
我是说  在别人面前
I mean, in front of someone else.
上次的时候我和他们差不多大
I wasn't much older than they are.
你自从小时候就没在别人面前露过脸了吗
You haven't shown your face to anyone since you were a kid?
没有过  他们收留我我很开心
No. I was happy that they took me in.
我父母被杀了  曼达洛人收留了我
My parents were killed and the Mandalorians took care of me.
很遗憾
I'm sorry.
此乃正道
This is the way.
有任何需要就告诉我们
Let us know if there's anything you need.
谢谢
Thank you.
大约有十五到二十人
About 15 or 20 of them
是徒步过来的
came through here on foot.
有个庞然大物把这些树枝撕碎了
And something big sheared off those branches.
AT-ST
AT-ST.
帝国的一种装甲兵器  全地形侦察步行机
帝国的步行机怎么会在这
Imperial walker. What's it doing here?
我不知道
I don't know.
但这已经超出我的能力范围了
But this is more than I signed up for.
坏消息  你们不能住在这了
Bad news. You can't live here anymore.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
你可真客气
Nice bedside manner.
你有更好的说法吗
You think you can do better?
想不出更坏的说法了
Can't do much worse.
我知道你们不希望听到这个消息
I know this is not the news you wanted to hear,
但你们别无选择
but there are no other options.
-你接下了这份活  -没错
- You took the job. - Yeah.
那是在我们知道AT-ST之前
That was before we knew about the AT-ST.
那是什么
What is that?
配备两门炮的武装步行机
The armored walker with two enormous guns
你们明明知道  但是没告诉我们
that you knew about and didn't tell us.
-帮帮我们  -求你了
- Help us. - Please.
-你应该是来帮我们的  -但我们雇了你
- You're supposed to help us. - But we hired you.
-求你了  -我们无处可去
- Please. - We have nowhere to go.
你们当然有地方去  这个星球很大
Sure you do. This is a big planet.
我还见过比这小得多的星球
I mean, I've seen a lot smaller.
我的祖辈给这些池塘播种
My grandparents seeded these ponds.
-好几代人的心血  -没错
- It took generations. - Yeah.
我理解  但我们只有两个人
I understand. I do. But there are only two of us.
不  那里至少还有二十个人
No, there's not. There's at least 20 here.
我是指战士  现实点吧
I mean fighters. Be realistic.
-我们可以学  -我们可以
- We can learn. - We can.
-给我们一次机会  -拜托了
- Give us a chance. - Please.
我曾经见过  那个东西在几分钟之内
I've seen that thing take out entire companies of soldiers
灭了成百的士兵
in a matter of minutes.
我们不会走
We're not leaving.
你们无法对抗它
You cannot fight that thing.
除非我们教他们怎么做
Unless we show them how.
让我们看看
Show us.
我们办得到
Yeah, we can do this.
你们有两个麻烦
You got two problems here.
强盗和机械
You got the bandits, and you got the mech.
我们会解决步行机
We'll handle the AT-ST,
当他们从树林里冲出来时  你们得掩护我们
but you gotta protect us when they come out of the woods.
我也不必再说他们有多危险
And I don't have to tell you how dangerous they are.
卡拉·杜恩是一名老兵
Cara Dune here was a veteran.
她曾是反抗军的伞兵
She was a drop soldier for the Rebellion,
她会为你们制定计划  仔细听好
and she's gonna lay out a plan for you, so listen carefully.
在这个星球上
Now, there's nothing on this planet
没有什么可以破坏步行机的腿
that can damage the legs on this thing,
所以我们要挖个陷阱
so we're gonna build a trap.
我们要在这里挖个很深的洞
We're gonna need to dig real deep, right here,
如果它踩到  就会掉下去
so that when it steps in, it drops.
我们两个会突袭他们的营地  引出他们
The two of us will hit their camp. Provoke them.
这样就可以把战斗地点从森林转移到我们这
That'll bring the fight out of the woods and down here to us.
我需要你们把树砍了
I'm gonna need you to cut down trees
在这些边缘处搭建障碍
and build barricades along these edges.
要足够高  让他们无法越过
I need it high enough so that they can't get over,
还要足够坚固  让他们无法突破
and strong enough so that it can't break through.
好了  谁会射击
Okay. Who knows how to shoot?
准备  一  把腿伸出来
Ready, one. Move your leg out.
准备好
Get ready.
一
One.
-伸出去  一  -开火
- Get into it. One. - Fire.
一
One.
二
Two.
三
Three.
四
Four.
还原
Reset.
再响一点
Louder.
一
One.
二
Two.
快要日落了
The sun is about to set,
我们很快就会出发
and we'll be leaving soon.
当我们回来时  速度会很快
When we return, we're coming in hot.
我们会准备好
We'll be ready.
快  我掩护你
Come on. I'll cover you.
希望计划能有用
I hope the plan worked.
跑  快跑
Go. Go!
没事的
It's okay.
来了
This is it.
一旦它走进池塘  就会陷下去
Once that thing steps into the pond, it's goin' down.
准备好武器
Weapons ready.
再等它走几步
Just a few more steps.
它停了
It stopped.
趴下  趴下
Get down. Get down.
卡本  待在那儿
Caben. Stay there.
守住你的位置
Hold your positions.
开火
Open fire.
我们得让那玩意继续走
We gotta get that thing to step forward.
我在想办法
I'm thinking.
退后  退后
Stay back, stay back!
新计划
New plan.
你有什么计划
What do you have in mind?
把脉冲步枪给我
Give me the pulse rifle.
我来掩护你
I'll cover you.
加油  你可以的
Come on, you got this.
来找老娘吧
Come to Mama.
现在不上就没机会了
This is it. It's now or never.
上啊
Go.
卡本  斯托克  上啊
Caben, Stoke, get out there.
上钩吧  你这个废物
Take the bait, you hunk of junk.
这也是计划吗
Was that the plan?
差不多吧
Somethin' like that.
谢谢
Thank you.
需要我在房子里添点东西吗
Can I set you something in the house?
谢谢  以后再说吧
Uh, thank you. Maybe later.
他在这里很开心
He's very happy here.
是的
He is.
适应得很好
Fits right in.
如果你把盔甲脱了会怎么样
So, what happens if you take that thing off?
盔甲会追杀你吗
They come after you and kill you?
不会  但我就穿不上了
No. You just can't ever put it back on again.
就这样
That's it?
所以你可以把头盔摘了
So you can slip off the helmet,
和那个漂亮的年轻寡妇安顿下来
and settle down with that beautiful young widow,
把你的孩子养大  坐在这里喝斯波奇茶
and raise your kid sitting here, sipping spotchka?
几周前我们在这里惹了不少麻烦
You know, we raised some hell here a few weeks back.
对于这样一个穷乡僻壤的小镇来说  动静太大了
It's too much action for a backwater town like this.
消息传得很快
Word travels fast.
我们可能得收拾一下离开这里了
We might wanna cycle the charts and move on.
我可不想告诉他这个消息
Would not wanna be the one who's gotta tell him.
我要把他留在这里
I'm leaving him here.
和我一起走  那孩子就过不上好日子了
Traveling with me, that's no life for a kid.
我完成任务了  他很安全  可以过上更好的生活
I did my job, he's safe. Better chance at a life.
来啊  来啊
Come on. Come on.
他肯定会难过的
It's gonna break his little heart.
他会撑过去的  我们都一样
He'll get over it. We all do.
不好意思  能和你聊聊吗
Excuse me. Can I have a word?
当然
Of course.
这里很好
It's very nice here.
对
Yes.
很明显  他在这里很开心
I think it's clear he's... He's happy here.
那你呢
What about you?
我
Me?
你在这里开心吗
Are you happy here?
我们希望你能留下来
We want you to stay.
社区很感激你
The community's grateful.
你可以把盔甲收起来  免得有麻烦
You can pack all this away in case there's ever trouble.
你和你的孩子可以过上好日子
You and your boy could have a good life.
不知道他什么时候才会长大
He could be a child for a while.
这不是很好吗
Wouldn't that be nice?
是的
It would.
我不属于这里
I don't belong here.
但他属于这里
But he does.
我明白
I understand.
我会像照顾自己的孩子一样照顾他
I will look after him as one of my own.
去找孩子们
Go get the kids.
他在追踪谁
Who's he tracking?
孩子
The kid.
他们知道孩子在这里
They know he's here.
对
Yes.
他们不会罢休的
Then they'll keep coming.
对
Yes.
你真的不需要护送吗
Are you sure you don't want an escort?
我很感谢你的提议
I appreciate the offer,
但我们要绕过城镇
but we're gonna bypass the town
直接前往刀锋之巅
and head right to the Razor Crest.
好吧  那我们有缘再见
Well then, until our paths cross.
有缘再见
Until our paths cross.
我会很想你的
I'm gonna miss you so much.
谢谢
Thank you.